hi guys Welcome to our YouTube channel
in today's video I am going to talk
about ICI Pro eye protect smart which is
a term insurance product offered by ICI
credential life insurance this is a
plain and simple term insurance plan
which protects your family in case you
are no more but is ICI Pro I protect a
smart a good choice if you are looking
for a term insurance plan what are its
benefits what are its pros and cons
let's find out to begin with with let's
talk about the insurance company which
is ICICI credential life insurance and
how it has been performing as an insurer
ICI Prudential life insurance is started
as a joint venture between ICI Bank
limited and credential Corporation
Holdings in the year 2001 and it started
operations in the same year it has been
in the business for more than two
decades and is a leading private life
insurer in
India talking about the claim settlement
ratio of ICI credential its last three
years average comes to around
97% this means that the company has been
settling on an average 970 claims out of
every thousand claims it received in the
last three years this is by itself a
decent number but one can argue that ICI
credential is lagging behind the other
top life insurers in India whose numbers
are a bit better coming to the volume of
claim complaints the company's last
three years average is around 4
this means that the company receives 14
claim complaints out of every 10,000
claims it receives this number is a bit
on the higher side as other top life
insurers perform much better when it
comes to dealing with claims the
operational metrics of ICI Prudential
life insurance look a bit dull when we
compare them with those of other top
life insurers in India but still they
are decent enough and better than
industry averages
now let's talk about the plan ICICI Pro
I protect a smart is a decent term
insurance plan which covers the most
basis the base life cover comes with an
inbuilt terminal illness benefit and
waver of Premium on permanent disability
terminal illness benefit automatically
accelerates your death benefit in case
you are diagnosed with a terminal
illness and your death benefit is paid
early while you are still alive this is
a good feature to have at no extra cost
but it is offered by almost all other
plans in the market faor of Premium on
permanent disability this feature waves
of all your premiums for all other
benefits in case you are diagnosed with
a permanent disability due to an
accident this feature lacks depth as it
does not cover disabilities due to
illness however this is a good benefit
to have as it comes with no extra cost
and you don't have to pay any extra
premium for it there is also a smart
exit benefit which allows you to close
your policy early and get all your
premiums paid back at no extra
cost this feature is available only if
you have already completed 25 years in
the policy and you still have five more
years to go ICICI Pro I protective smart
does not come with other common features
offered by other plans in the market
such as spouse cover or increasing or
top of cover options however you have
the option to increase your life cover
on the occurrence of a life event such
as marriage or having a
baby now there are two additional
benefits which come as Rider and you can
add them by paying some extra premium
first one is accidental death benefit
which is a great option to enhance your
cover significantly by paying very
little extra premium if you have this
benefit added accidental death benefit
is paid to your family in addition to
the base benefit in case the death
happens due to an accident another one
is critical illness Rider ICI Prudential
life insurance offers only one variant
of critical illness Rider along with its
term plan which is an accelerated
benefit this Rider covers only 34 listed
critical illnesses if you opt for this
Rider a portion of your death benefit is
accelerated and paid early in case you
are diagnosed with any one of these 34
listed critical
illnesses this benefit is only paid to
the extent of CI Rider benefit the
remaining portion of your death benefit
is paid to your family only after your
demise this is a very basic CI Rider as
there is only one option to choose from
and moreover this is an accelerated
benefit and covers only 34 illnesses
other life insurers in India offer much
better and more comprehensive options
now an important question arises which
is how much does this plan cost does it
offer competitive
pricing if you are looking for the basic
coverage of rupees 50 lakh or 1 CR this
may not be the cheapest plan in the
market however if you're looking for a
coverage of rupees 2 CR or more this
plan becomes quite competitive and for
certain combinations of age and term
this could even be the cheapest option
available now let's come down to the
final and most important question should
you buy ICI Pro eye protector smart as
we have already seen this plan does not
offer much customization as the rider
and add-on benefits offered by the
company are limited and
basic however the plan covers most bases
well and it is one of the most
competitive plans if you are going for a
term cover of rupees 2 CR or more if you
can ignore the slightly higher volumes
of claim complaints faced by ICICI
Prudential Life Insurance this is one of
the good plans in the market if you are
looking for a term cover of rupees 2 CR
or more moreover the insurer enjoys good
brand reputation as it is backed by a
large private bank which is icci bank so
guys this was it from my site today if
you like this video please like and
share it with your family and friends
and don't forget to subscribe to this
channel I'll see you in another video
and till then bye-bye